Hello friends, how are you all?  I hope it will be
quite good.  So friends, the
IPO of ICIC Pensal AMC has opened
and it also has share holder quota.
So, many
people have different questions in their mind regarding the share holder quota as to
who all are eligible.  Ok?
How many applications can I apply?
How can we increase our chances so that we can
place our bets in such a way that our chances increase.
And
how will allotment be received within the shareholder quota?  Whether it will be available on lottery basis
or proportionate basis, you will
know all these things in this video.
Before starting the video, friends, the
links of Telegram, Instagram, WhatsApp, Facebook are inside the description.  Join and
keep it.  So first of all let us start
with who all are eligible?  If you are
eligible then this video will be useful for you.
So first of all let us start with
who is eligible for the shareholder quota
?  So see, those who have ICICI Bank
shares, that is, even one share,
are eligible for shareholder quota, but when did you buy it now?
No, you must have bought it on December 4. If
you bought it on December 4 or anytime before that,
that share should remain in your demat account till December 5.
If you had
that share of ICICI Bank in your demat account till December 5, then you are
eligible for shareholder quota. So this
thing is clear. Whether you are eligible or not, please do let
me know by commenting
because its RHP filing date
was December 6, so December 6 was
Friday, December 5 was Saturday.
What is the reason for this, the share should be in our demat account till December 5. So,
whoever bought on December 4, the same will be
in his demat account on December 5
because delivery happens after 1 day. This thing is
clear. Whoever bought on the last 4th date
or bought before that
is eligible.  Now how will you know whether you are eligible or not,
how to confirm it, so see,
many people must have received the mail that you
are eligible for the share holder quota, okay,
your mail comes on the email ID.
Wherever our PAN card or email ID is given
in the demat account, the company people like
ICICI AMC send you a message
that you are eligible for the shareholder quota.
Second thing is that you may
not have received the mail.  Brother, if people do not receive mail then are
we not eligible?  No.   It's not like that.
If you have purchased shares on December 4
or before that, you did
not receive the mail.  Sometimes the mail does not arrive.
Ok?  Sometimes you
can also check under spam etc.  Whether you have received the mail there
or not, you
are eligible and can still apply.  This thing
is also clear because if we take it on 4th December and it will be
in our demat account on 5th December, then we will automatically become eligible.
Meaning you have to take only one share.  So there is
no need to worry whether the mail comes or not.
What is the benefit now?  Brother, our third
question is
what is the benefit of applying under the shareholder category?
How can we benefit from this?  So see, the
advantage in this is that you
can apply for IPO twice.  You can apply two applications.
Generally, in any normal
IPO, we apply for only one application.
If there are two applications, it means
application means that no matter how many lots you
place, even if you place an application of Rs 10 lakh, there should be only
one.  It should be from the same demat account.
Some people say that if you apply one with this
, then apply the other with that, it gets rejected.  This will
not happen inside it.
What will happen in this is that if you
can submit two applications then the chances of allotment will
double.  Now, inside this, you can
invest in the Plus Shareholder category under the Retail category or you can invest in the
Plus Shareholder category under the Small HAI category
or you can invest in the
Plus Shareholder category under the Big HAI category, that is,
you can apply according to the amount of funds available with you.
Retail small HAI HA big HAI,
you do this normally.  You have applied one of them
plus the application for share holder
quota, you can apply another one.
Now you know
what happens in the retail category that
applications below Rs 2 lakh have to be made.
Under Small HA, an application of between Rs 2 lakh to Rs 10 lakh has to be
made.  And under the Big HAI
category, applications worth more than Rs 10 lakh have to be
submitted.  This thing
is normally clear to you.  But
what is the limit within the shareholder category?
How many last lots can we apply maximum
?  This is also a confusion in the minds of people.
So see, the limit within the share holder category
is under 2 lakhs.
You can apply for any number of lots within Rs 2 lakh.
That makes 15 lots
worth approximately ₹194850.  You can invest maximum 15 lots within the share holder
category.  Not more than that.  If you
invest more than that, you will
not be eligible for the shareholder category.   This
means that whatever your application is, it will
not be counted under the shareholder category.
So keep this in mind
that you have to invest only under Rs 2 lakh.
If you apply under the shareholder category.
So
this application was installed within Rs 2 lakh.  Rest,
whatever you apply for in Retail Small H Chennai Big Chennai
above Rs 10 lakh, you
can do it separately.  In this,
keep in mind that within the shareholder quota, the maximum is 15 lots.
You can invest one lot, two lots, even if the
maximum is 15 lots, below 2 lakhs. This
thing is also clear, that is why I am repeating it,
many people do not understand many things.
Many people get it at one time.
Many people already know this thing.  That's why
I am repeating it.
What is everyone so much that they are not wise.  That's why
I am repeating it again and again.
Now how will allotment be received inside this?  See, in the
normal category of Retail, Small, HNI,
Big HA, allotment is done
on lottery basis.  No matter how many lots we
apply for, whether one or 1 crore,
what we get in it is that
we will get allotment only on lottery basis.  This thing
became clear.  This has happened on the side,
retail small HAI and big HAI.  Now, in the
shareholder category, generally it happens
that we get allotment on proportionate basis
and in this also it is the same
that we will get allotment on proportionate basis.
Now many people may
not know the proportionate basis, let me tell you that also.
So suppose we have applied 10 lots.  I am
telling you for example.
We applied for 10 lots within this shareholder category.
And
how much of the shareholder category was subscribed?  It got subscribed 15 times.
Ok?  It got subscribed 15 times.
How many did we apply for
?  10 So what are the chances of allotment
?  10/15 so that makes approximately around 67%.
So there will be chances of getting a lot in this.
Meaning the chances are a little
higher.  According to this,
allotment will be given on proportionate basis.  And if it gets subscribed 15 times
and you apply for 15 lots, then
you will get one confirmed lot.  So
this is the thing.  So,
if you apply for a few more allotments within the share holder category,
maximum 15, then
your chances of allotment will be higher.  So
if you want to try and get more
money, if you have up to Rs 2 lakh, then you can
allot more money in this way that you
apply within the shareholder category only.  So it will
benefit you more.  You will definitely get confirmed allotment inside it.
Ok?
Because it is on proportionate basis.  Invest the
remaining money in retail or
Chennai, whichever you like.
Now it is clear that many people
ask how to increase the chances of allotment
?  So in this way
your chances of allotment can increase.  You should
apply for the maximum lot within the shareholder category.  Only
one lot will be available inside it.   You wo
n't get much.  You
cannot expect much from this.  Only one lot will be available.
But almost everyone will get it.  Rest, whatever
allotment you get in the normal category is a
matter of your luck.  Now another question is
that we will apply for the shareholder category
but
what is the reserved quota for them?  So, a
reserve quota of only 5% has been kept for them.  But
5% is not less.  The issue size is ₹100 crore.
So 5% comes to approximately ₹530 crore.
So ₹530 crore is the normal
issue size of an IPO.  They have kept that size
for the shareholder quota.  So that's a
good thing.  The chances
of getting this allotment are quite high because there is no
application worth Rs 10 lakh in it.
Whatever the application is, it is below 2 lakhs,
why do they keep it below 2 lakhs?  So that all the
retailers etc.,
small investors can benefit.
If
more applications are kept for the shareholder category, then what will happen is
that big players will come and they will
fill it directly and they will benefit.  So
what is the reason that to give benefit to everyone,
applications below Rs 2 lakh are kept
so that everyone can get benefit.  So 5% has been kept as
reserved quota.  24.48 lakh shares 24.48 lakh
shares have been reserved
for the shareholders.  This thing also became clear.
So these are the answers to all the questions regarding overall shareholder quota.
I have answered almost all your
questions.  Now if
you have any other question then
please let us know by commenting.  I will read it
and maybe I will discuss it in the next video.
So this thing is
clear to you.  Whoever has done the last
buy of ICICI Bank shares till 4th December
is eligible and within the shareholder quota,
application has to be placed within the maximum of Rs 2 lakh,
maximum 15 lots is fine, allotment will be given
on proportionate basis within the shareholder quota,
this thing is also clear, meaning the
more lots you place, the more will be the
benefit within the shareholder quota and if you want to
increase the chances of allotment, then
focus more on the shareholder quota,
this thing is clear, now if you
liked the video, do like it and subscribe to the channel, we will
meet friends in the next
video, if you have any other query,
please do let us know by commenting.